

Summary

University of Toronto full stack web development bootcamp graduate with a final grade of 100.8%. The program allowed me to hone skills in creativity, abstract thinking, and learning - I also found I had a knack for fixing bugs. Through previous experience as a manager, I developed strengths in leadership, planning, and teamwork. These skills proved very useful throughout team projects, during which I relied on my communication, organization, and relational skills to work congruently with others and ensure we met our goals.

Education

Full Stack Web Development University of Toronto

May 2022 to Oct. 2022

A twenty four week intensive bootcamp course focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and the MERN Stack

Projects

InnerPattern (group)

Oct. 2022 to Oct. 2022

- MERN stack single-page application utilizing Apollo and GraphQL for specific database queries, JWT for authentication, and bcrypt for password security.
- During development I worked to facilitate communication, organization, and goal setting. This helped our team stay on track to create a high quality, finished product that we were proud of.
- · Users are able to log in and create, read, update, and delete journal entries which are tied to their account.

Weather App

June 2022 to June 2022

- · Weather forecast search-engine developed using jQuery, HTML, CSS, and integrated with an existing weather API.
- Using jQuery and the object oriented programming paradigm, I simplified my functions showing a clear flow of execution, reducing total code and increasing readability.
- Users are able to search for any city around the world and view it's current weather, including a 5 day forecast projection.

Tech Bits Aug. 2022 to Aug. 2022

- A CMS-style blog site utilizing MySQL and sequelize for the backend, express-session for authentication, and handlebars for rendering.
- Users are able to create an account and perform all CRUD operations on user posts.

Employment

Manager

Oshawa, ON Oct. 2021 to July 2022

- · Redesigned the training and work procedure which reduced mistakes and customer complaints.
- Transformed the garage culture to a positive work environment.
- Reorganized the garage to make everything more accessible, which made everyone's job easier and more efficient.
- $\bullet \ \mbox{Reprioritized inventory, which made ordering easier and saved the owner money.}$

Tire and Lube Technician

Oil Changers

Oil Changers

Oshawa, ON

Jan. 2021 to Oct. 2021

• Helped coworkers and provided customer service, saving the company from costly mistakes and bad reputation - and customers from any issues.

Lawn Maintenance (self-employed)

Durham Lawn Co

Durham Region, ON Apr. 2020 to Sept. 2020

- Built client base from a very positive reputation where I was considered reliable, friendly, and performed quality work
- Researched equipment and taught self business and maintenance techniques via internet.

Team Leader | Utility Relief | Line Worker

General Motors

Oshawa, ON

Oct. 2015 to Jan. 2020

- Learned things quickly and was relied on to keep different teams functioning and operating smoothly.
- Continuously learned different jobs within plant to provide relief and training to coworkers.
- Worked to create a positive work environment wherever I was positioned.

Contact



tylerscottdev@gmail.com

React-SPA-Portfolio

**** 2899436850

Oshawa, Ontario

in tylerscottdev

Tyl3r-s

Skills

LANGUAGES

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

React

Express

Bootstrap

jQuery

Node

Handlebars

DATABASES

MySQL

MongoDB

GraphQL

TOOLS

Git

Web API

Third-Party API

RESTful API

Sequelize

Mongoose

Webpack

Babel npm

fiama

jest

PARADIGMS & ARCHITECTURES

Object Oriented Programming

Model View Controller

Functional Programming

Object Relational Mapping

PRINCIPLES

Separation of Concerns

Keep it Simple

Don't Repeat Yourself

Refactoring

Documentation

Clean Code

Agile

SCRUM

Mobile First Design

Test Driven Deployment